sitevisibility.co.uk 2019-07-03

# Cookie and Privacy Policy - SiteVisibility

Updated: October 24 2018.  
For any questions regarding our privacy policy and use of data, please email [marketing@sitevisibility.com](mailto:marketing@sitevisibility.com) or call 01273 733 433.

## Introduction

Welcome to the SiteVisibility’s privacy policy.

We respect your privacy and are committed to protecting your personal data.

This privacy policy will inform you about:

  * the data collected by the company, SiteVisibility;
  * how it is used;
  * how it is protected;
  * your ability to control the collection and use of your personal data;
  * your privacy rights; and
  * how the law protects you.

SiteVisibility (SiteVisibility Marketing Ltd) is registered with the Office of the Information Commissioner Data Protection Act 2003. Our registration number is Z1082412.

### **Data Controller**

SiteVisibility Marketing Ltd is the data controller and responsible for your personal data (collectively referred to as “SiteVisibility”, “we”, “us” or “our” in this privacy policy).

SiteVisibility is registered with the Office of the Information Commissioner Data Protection Act 2003. Our registration number is Z1082412.

### **Contact details**

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or our privacy practices, please contact in the following ways:

Email address: [marketing@sitevisibility.com](mailto:marketing@sitevisibility.com)

Postal address: SiteVisibility

King Place Suite,

3 King Place

Brighton

East Sussex

BN1 1GA

Telephone number: 01273 733 433

You have the right to make a complaint at any time to the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO), the UK supervisory authority for data protection issues (www.ico.org.uk). We would, however, appreciate the chance to deal with your concerns before you approach the ICO so please contact us in the first instance.

Changes to the privacy policy and your duty to inform us of changes

We keep our privacy policy under regular review. This version was last updated on 24/10/2018.

It is important that the personal data we hold about you is accurate and current. Please keep us informed if your personal data changes during your relationship with us.

### **Third-party links**

This website may include links to third-party websites, plug-ins and applications. Clicking on those links or enabling those connections may allow third parties to collect or share data about you. We do not control these third-party websites and are not responsible for their privacy statements. When you leave our website, we encourage you to read the privacy policy of every website you visit.

## What Information SiteVisibility Collects

### Anonymous data

We collect anonymous information about the visitors to our website via Google Analytics for analytics purposes. This is never personally identifiable information. For more information on Google’s practices to safeguard your data, [please visit this link](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en).

The information collected from visitors to the website is anonymous and is used for tracking purposes to determine, for example, the number of pages visited in the session, the length of time spent on each page, and the frequency of visits to the website.

### Personal data

Personal data, or personal information, means any information about an individual from which that person can be identified. It does not include data where the identity has been removed (anonymous data – see above).

We may collect, use, store and transfer different kinds of personal data about you as follows:

  * **Identity Data** includes [first name, maiden name, last name, username or similar identifier, marital status, title, date of birth and gender].
  * **Contact Data** includes [email address and telephone numbers].
  * **Technical Data** includes [internet protocol (IP) address, browser type and version, time zone setting and location, browser plug-in types and versions, operating system and platform, and other technology on the devices you use to access this website].
  * **Usage Data** includes [information about how you use our website, products and services].
  * **Marketing and Communications Data** includes [your preferences in receiving marketing from us and our third parties and your communication preferences].

Personal information is only collected from users who provide this information when they submit it via our contact forms, live chat requests, or sometimes those who provide information over the phone when calling with an inquiry.

We do not collect any special categories of personal data about you (this includes details about your race or ethnicity, religious or philosophical beliefs, sex life, sexual orientation, political opinions, trade union membership, information about your health, and genetic and biometric data). Nor do we collect any information about criminal convictions and offences.

**If you fail to provide personal data**

Where we need to collect personal data by law, or under the terms of a contract we have with you, and you fail to provide that data when requested, we may not be able to perform the contract we have or are trying to enter into with you (for example, to provide you with goods or services). In this case, we may have to cancel a product or service you have with us but we will notify you if this is the case at the time.

Once a visitor completes the contact form, accesses information behind a ‘wall’ (where the user must provide their personal details such as an email address) or contacts the company by live chat, email or phone, any data coming from that exchange will be recorded and kept in our database. This data is never shared with any third-party (other than the database provider)

### **How we collect your personal data**

We use different methods to collect data from and about you including through:

  * **Direct interactions.** You may give us your Identity, Contact and Financial Data by filling in forms or by corresponding with us by post, phone, email or otherwise. This includes personal data you provide when you:
  * Request information on our products or services;
  * create an account on our website;
  * subscribe to our service or publications;
  * request marketing assets to be sent to you;
  * enter a competition, promotion or survey; or
  * give us feedback or contact us.
  * **Automated technologies or interactions.** As you interact with our website, we will automatically collect Technical Data about your equipment, browsing actions and patterns. We collect this personal data by using cookies, server logs and other similar technologies.

**Third parties or publicly available sources.** We will receive personal data about you from various third parties and public sources. For example, analytics providers (such as Google based outside the EU).

## How SiteVisibility Uses the Collected Information

We will only use your personal data when the law allows us to. Most commonly, we will use your personal data in the following circumstances:

  * Where we need to perform the contract we are about to enter into or have entered into with you.
  * Where it is necessary for our legitimate interests (or those of a third party) and your interests and fundamental rights do not override those interests.
  * Where we need to comply with a legal obligation.

Generally, we do not rely on consent as a legal basis for processing your personal data. You have the right to withdraw consent to marketing at any time by contacting us.

We have set out below, in a table format, a description of all the ways we plan to use your personal data, and which of the legal bases we rely on to do so. We have also identified what our legitimate interests are where appropriate.

Note that we may process your personal data for more than one lawful ground depending on the specific purpose for which we are using your data. Please contact us if you need details about the specific legal ground we are relying on to process your personal data where more than one ground has been set out in the table below.

**Purpose/Activity** | **Type of data** | **Lawful basis for processing including basis of legitimate interest**  
---|---|---  
To register you as a new customer | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

| Performance of a contract with you  
To manage our relationship with you which will include: 

(a) Notifying you about changes to our terms or privacy policy

(b) Asking you to leave a review or take a survey

| (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Marketing and Communications

| (a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation

(c) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to keep our records updated and to study how customers use our products/services)  
  
To enable you to partake in a prize draw, competition or complete a survey | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

| (a) Performance of a contract with you 

(b) Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them and grow our business)  
  
To administer and protect our business and this website (including troubleshooting, data analysis, testing, system maintenance, support, reporting and hosting of data) | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

| (a) Necessary for our legitimate interests (for running our business, provision of administration and IT services, network security, to prevent fraud and in the context of a business reorganisation or group restructuring exercise) 

(b) Necessary to comply with a legal obligation  
  
To deliver relevant website content and advertisements to you and measure or understand the effectiveness of the advertising we serve to you | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Profile

(d) Usage

(e) Marketing and Communications

(f) Technical

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to study how customers use our products/services, to develop them, to grow our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To use data analytics to improve our website, products/services, marketing, customer relationships and experiences | (a) Technical 

(b) Usage

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to define types of customers for our products and services, to keep our website updated and relevant, to develop our business and to inform our marketing strategy)  
To make suggestions and recommendations to you about goods or services that may be of interest to you | (a) Identity 

(b) Contact

(c) Technical

(d) Usage

(e) Profile

(f) Marketing and Communications

| Necessary for our legitimate interests (to develop our products/services and grow our business)  
  
We use your personal data in the following specific ways:

**Hotjar**

We use an analytics tool called  **Hotjar**  in order to better understand our users’ needs and to optimise our website experience. Hotjar is a technology service that helps us better understand our users experience (e.g. how much time they spend on which pages, which links they choose to click, what users do and don’t like, etc.) and this enables us to build and maintain our service with user feedback. Hotjar uses cookies and other technologies to collect data on our users’ behavior and their devices (in particular device’s IP address (captured and stored only in anonymized form), device screen size, device type (unique device identifiers), browser information, geographic location (country only), preferred language used to display our website). Hotjar stores this information in a pseudonymized user profile. Neither Hotjar nor we will ever use this information to identify individual users or to match it with further data on an individual user. For further details, please see Hotjar’s privacy policy by clicking on [this link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/policies/privacy).

You can opt-out to the creation of a user profile, Hotjar’s storing of data about your usage of our site and Hotjar’s use of tracking cookies on other websites by following this [opt-out link](https://www.hotjar.com/legal/compliance/opt-out).

**Intercom (our live chat function)**

**Use of Intercom Services:**  We use third-party analytics services to help understand your usage of our services. In particular, we provide a limited amount of your information (such as sign-up date and some personal information like your email address) to Intercom, Inc. (“Intercom”) and utilize Intercom to collect data for analytics purposes when you visit our website or use our product. As a data processor acting on our behalf, Intercom analyzes your use of our website and/or product and tracks our relationship by way of cookies and similar technologies so that we can improve our service to you. For more information on Intercom’s use of cookies, please visit <https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#cookie-policy>. We may also use Intercom as a medium for communications, either through email, or through messages within our product(s). As part of our service agreements, Intercom collects publicly available contact and social information related to you, such as your email address, gender, company, job title, photos, website URLs, social network handles and physical addresses, to enhance your user experience. For more information on the privacy practices of Intercom, please visit [https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#privacy](https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/zMP6C0glXI29np7TOQGei?domain=intercom.com). Intercom’s services are governed by Intercom’s terms of use which can be found at [https://www.intercom.com/terms-and-policies#terms](https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/_s9hCg5BQCljvDoc7KDEG?domain=intercom.com). If you would like to opt out of having this information collected by or submitted to Intercom, please contact us.

**Google Analytics**

The information collected anonymously for the purposes of Google Analytics enables us to improve user experience.

The information we collect is used to generate reports to make the site more user friendly and to determine which types of content are most appealing for our users.

Any personal information that’s collected via our contact forms or live chat requests is used solely for the purpose of providing users with marketing news and resources (if they’ve opted in to our mailing list) or to enable us to contact them if they’ve sought information on our products and services.

We will only use your personal data for the purposes for which we collected it, unless we reasonably consider that we need to use it for another reason and that reason is compatible with the original purpose.

If we need to use your personal data for an unrelated purpose, we will notify you and we will explain the legal basis which allows us to do so.

Please note that we may process your personal data without your knowledge or consent, in compliance with the above rules, where this is required or permitted by law.

**Will The Company Contact You?**

We strive to provide you with choices regarding certain personal data uses, particularly around marketing and advertising.

We may use your Identity, Contact, Technical, Usage and Profile Data to form a view on what we think you may want or need, or what may be of interest to you. This is how we decide which products, services and offers may be relevant for you.

When completing any of the contact forms or entering into a live chat request or submitting a request for information, you consent to the company contacting you about our products and services.

You will only receive updates on marketing news, offers and resources if you double opt-in to our mailing list.

**Opting out**

You will always be given the opportunity to unsubscribe if you no longer want to receive these updates. If ever you’re having problems unsubscribing, you can contact us by calling us on 01273 733 433 or by emailing [marketing@sitevisibility.com](mailto:marketing@sitevisibility.com).

**Cookies**

You can set your browser to refuse all or some browser cookies, or to alert you when websites set or access cookies. If you disable or refuse cookies, please note that some parts of this website may become inaccessible or not function properly.

## **Sharing Your Information**

We will not sell your information, trade it with any other third party, or use it for any other purpose other than to communicate to you offers about our service offerings, or closely related events or opportunities we would reasonably consider you to have an interest in based on your initial or any subsequent requests.

## **Data Security**

We have put in place appropriate security measures to prevent your personal data from being accidentally lost, used or accessed in an unauthorised way, altered or disclosed. In addition, we limit access to your personal data to those employees, agents, contractors and other third parties who have a business need to know. They will only process your personal data on our instructions and they are subject to a duty of confidentiality.

We have put in place procedures to deal with any suspected personal data breach and will notify you and any applicable regulator of a breach where we are legally required to do so.

## **How Long Will We Keep Your Data**

We will hold your personal information on our systems for only as long as is necessary for the relevant activity (for example – a sales process), or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with us. We will keep your data in the database unless you request otherwise removed. We may retain your personal data for a longer period in the event of a complaint or if we reasonably believe there is a prospect of litigation in respect to our relationship with you. We regularly update our database to remove data that’s no longer required.

To determine the appropriate retention period for personal data, we consider the amount, nature and sensitivity of the personal data, the potential risk of harm from unauthorised use or disclosure of your personal data, the purposes for which we process your personal data and whether we can achieve those purposes through other means, and the applicable legal, regulatory, tax, accounting or other requirements.

In some circumstances you can ask us to delete your data: see [your legal rights] below for further information.

In some circumstances we will anonymise your personal data (so that it can no longer be associated with you) for research or statistical purposes, in which case we may use this information indefinitely without further notice to you.

The anonymous data that we collect via Google Analytics is kept for 26 months. This data retention window is reset with every new engagement a user makes with our website. Please visit [this link](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/7667196?hl=en) for more information.

## **Your legal rights**

Under certain circumstances, you have rights under data protection laws in relation to your personal data as follows:

  * **Request access** to your personal data (commonly known as a “data subject access request”). This enables you to receive a copy of the personal data we hold about you and to check that we are lawfully processing it.
  * **Request correction** of the personal data that we hold about you. This enables you to have any incomplete or inaccurate data we hold about you corrected, though we may need to verify the accuracy of the new data you provide to us.
  * **Request erasure** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to delete or remove personal data where there is no good reason for us continuing to process it. You also have the right to ask us to delete or remove your personal data where you have successfully exercised your right to object to processing (see below), where we may have processed your information unlawfully or where we are required to erase your personal data to comply with local law. Note, however, that we may not always be able to comply with your request of erasure for specific legal reasons which will be notified to you, if applicable, at the time of your request.
  * **Object to processing** of your personal data where we are relying on a legitimate interest (or those of a third party) and there is something about your particular situation which makes you want to object to processing on this ground as you feel it impacts on your fundamental rights and freedoms. You also have the right to object where we are processing your personal data for direct marketing purposes. In some cases, we may demonstrate that we have compelling legitimate grounds to process your information which override your rights and freedoms.
  * **Request restriction of processing** of your personal data. This enables you to ask us to suspend the processing of your personal data in the following scenarios:

If you want us to establish the data’s accuracy.

Where our use of the data is unlawful but you do not want us to erase it.

Where you need us to hold the data even if we no longer require it as you need it to establish, exercise or defend legal claims.

You have objected to our use of your data but we need to verify whether we have overriding legitimate grounds to use it.

  * **Request the transfer** of your personal data to you or to a third party. We will provide to you, or a third party you have chosen, your personal data in a structured, commonly used, machine-readable format. Note that this right only applies to automated information which you initially provided consent for us to use or where we used the information to perform a contract with you.
  * **Withdraw consent at any time** where we are relying on consent to process your personal data. However, this will not affect the lawfulness of any processing carried out before you withdraw your consent. If you withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide certain products or services to you. We will advise you if this is the case at the time you withdraw your consent.

If you wish to exercise any of the rights set out above, please contact us at [marketing@sitevisibility.com](mailto:marketing@sitevisibility.com) **AND** [jason.woodford@sitevisibility.com](mailto:jason.woodford@sitevisibility.com).

**No fee usually required**

You will not have to pay a fee to access your personal data (or to exercise any of the other rights). However, we may charge a reasonable fee if your request is clearly unfounded, repetitive or excessive. Alternatively, we could refuse to comply with your request in these circumstances.

**What we may need from you**

We may need to request specific information from you to help us confirm your identity and ensure your right to access your personal data (or to exercise any of your other rights). This is a security measure to ensure that personal data is not disclosed to any person who has no right to receive it. We may also contact you to ask you for further information in relation to your request to speed up our response.

**Time limit to respond**

We try to respond to all legitimate requests within one month. Occasionally it could take us longer than a month if your request is particularly complex or you have made a number of requests. In this case, we will notify you and keep you updated.

## Will The Company Contact You?

By completing any of the contact forms or entering into a live chat request and submitting a request for information, you enable the company to contact you about their products and services.

You will only receive updates on marketing news, offers and resources if you double opt-in to our mailing list. You will always be given the opportunity to unsubscribe if you no longer want to receive these updates. If ever you’re having problems unsubscribing, you can contact us by calling us on 01273 733 433 or by emailing [marketing@sitevisibility.com](mailto:marketing@sitevisibility.com)

## Sharing Your Information

We will not sell your information, trade it with any other third party, or use it for any other purpose other than to communicate to you offers about our service offerings, or closely related events or opportunities we would reasonably consider you to have an interest in based on your initial or any subsequent requests.

## How Long Will We Keep Your Data

We will hold your personal information on our systems for as long as is necessary for the relevant activity (for example – a sales process), or as long as is set out in any relevant contract you hold with us. We will keep your data in the database unless you request otherwise removed. We regularly update our database to remove data that’s no longer required.

The anonymous data that we collect via Google Analytics is kept for 26 months. This data retention window is reset with every new engagement a user makes with our website. Please visit [this link](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/7667196?hl=en) for more information.

## Cookies

In May 2011, the UK Government passed new legislation is regards to the use of Cookies. The following section explains what cookies are, which ones are collected by SiteVisibility and how they are used on SiteVisibility’s website.

## How We Collect Information

Cookies are small text files that are placed on your computer by the websites that you visit. They are commonly used in order to make websites work by tracking goods that you have placed in a basket, or work more efficiently by remembering your login details, as well as to provide information about the sites usage to the owners of the site.

## Types of Cookies

There are three types of cookies dropped and collected by websites. With some exceptions (i.e.  websites that fundamentally require cookies in order for website functionality – see below) from 26th May 2012, all cookies must be consented to by a site’s users.

**Cookie Type**

| 

**Description**  
  
---|---  
  
Moderately intrusive

| 

Embedded third-party content and social

media-plugins

Advertising campaign optimisation  
  
Minimally intrusive

| 

Web analytics / metrics

Personalised content / interface  
  
Necessary for Website Functionality

(Exempt from changes to privacy regulations)

| 

Stop multiple form submissions

Load balancing

Transaction specific  
  
SiteVisibility collects the following anonymous cookies for tracking purposes.

**Name**

| 

**Description**

| 

**Expiration**  
  
---|---|---  
__utma | This cookie is typically written to the browser upon the first visit to your site  _from that web browser_. If the cookie has been deleted by the browser operator, and the browser subsequently visits your site, a new __utma cookie is written with a different unique ID. This cookie is used to determine unique visitors to your site and it is updated with each page view. Additionally, this cookie is provided with a unique ID that Google Analytics uses to ensure both the validity and accessibility of the cookie as an extra security measure. | 2 years from set/update.  
__utmb | This cookie is used to establish and continue a user session with your site. When a user views a page on your site, the Google Analytics code attempts to update this cookie. If it does not find the cookie, a new one is written and a new session is established. Each time a user visits a different page on your site, this cookie is updated to expire in 30 minutes, thus continuing a single session for as long as user activity continues within 30-minute intervals. This cookie expires when a user pauses on a page on your site for longer than 30 minutes. You can modify the default length of a user session with the [_setSessionCookieTimeout()](https://developers.google.com/analytics/devguides/collection/gajs/methods/gaJSApiBasicConfiguration#_gat.GA_Tracker_._setSessionCookieTimeout) method. | 30 minutes from set/update.  
__utmc | This cookie is no longer used by the ga.js tracking code to determine session status.Historically, this cookie operated in conjunction with the __utmb cookie to determine whether or not to establish a new session for the user. For backwards compatibility purposes with sites still using the urchin.js tracking code, this cookie will continue to be written and will expire when the user exits the browser. However, if you are debugging your site tracking and you use the ga.js tracking code, you should not interpret the existence of this cookie in relation to a new or expired session. | Not set.  
__utmz | This cookie stores the type of referral used by the visitor to reach your site, whether via a direct method, a referring link, a website search, or a campaign such as an ad or an email link. It is used to calculate search engine traffic, ad campaigns and page navigation within your own site. The cookie is updated with each page view to your site. | 6 months from set/update.  
  
## WordPress Cookies

WordPress websites also collect cookies for commenters. As the SiteVisibility website is built using WordPress, these cookies apply to our users.

When visitors comment on the SiteVisibility blog, they will have cookies stored on their computer. This is purely for convenience, so that the visitor will not be required to re-type all their information again when they want to leave another comment in the future.

Three cookies are set for commenters:

comment_author

comment_author_email

comment_author_url

The commenter cookies are set to expire a little less than one year from the time they’re set.

## Third Party Cookies

Users of the site who wish to share SiteVisibility’s content socially using Facebook, Twitter, or Google+ (the platforms which are currently enabled on the website to allow this function) may have cookies stored on their computers from these third party websites.

Cookies are collected from third party sites so that you can be logged in to your account on their site and share our content simply and easily.

For more information on the cookie policies of these third party sites, please visit their websites. You will be able to control the way cookies are used when you are signed into your accounts on these sites through the privacy settings they have made available to you.

Facebook Privacy Policy (<https://www.facebook.com/about/privacy/other>)

Twitter Privacy Policy (<https://twitter.com/privacy>)

Google+ Privacy Policy (<http://www.google.co.uk/intl/en/policies/privacy/>)

LinkedIn Privacy Policy (<https://www.linkedin.com/legal/privacy-policy>)

## Prohibiting the Collection of Cookies

If you would like to prevent SiteVisibility from collecting cookies when you visit our site, please update your privacy settings in your browser. You can control the kinds of cookies you accept there.

<http://www.google.co.uk/goodtoknow/manage-data/>

<http://www.mozilla.org/en-US/privacy/>

<http://privacy.microsoft.com/en-gb/default.mspx>
